Guide to the David Bates papers, 1940-1998 MS0218.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
David Bates papers
1940-1998
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS0218.UA
1.5 Linear Feet
David M. Bates (1925- ) was born in Arlington, Virginia. He graduated from The George Washington University in 1946, and while a student was very active in the Glee Club, directed by Dr. Robert Harmon. Collection includes essays, and photographs ranging in date from 1940-1998
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated to the University Archives in two accessions by Mr. David Bates in 1994 and 1999.
Biographical Note
David M. Bates (1925- ) was born in Arlington, Virginia. He graduated from The George Washington University in 1946, and while a student was very active in the Glee Club, directed by Dr. Robert Harmon. Many years later he was still active with his alma mater, working as a volunteer in the Gelman Library's University Archives to organize materials related to the glee club and choral music, and indexed the student newspaper, The Hatchet for citations relating to the subject.
Bates also participated in choral music reunions, most notably in 1986, and for years was the secretary/historian of the Harmon Choral Associates, an alumni group which supported the music program at GW. Bates wrote seven short essays in the 1990s related to his family and memories of growing up in Washington and attending GW, which are helpful tools to people reasearching that era.
An oral history done with Mr. Bates in 1989 can be found in MS0371, the Oral History Collection.
N.B. This history note was written in 2005.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include essays and photographs. They range in date from 1940-1998, and were donated to the University Archives in two accessions by Mr. David Bates in 1994 and 1999.
Collection Organization
Organized into two series: Papers and Photographs
Washington (D.C.); Arlington (Va.); United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Choral music; Photographs; World War, 1939-1945; Harmon, Robert; George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae; Bates, David M.; George Washington University--History
- Papers, 1940-1998; MS0218 Series 1; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of seven papers written by David Bates (GW class of 1946) on GW, Washington, and Arlington in World War II. The materials range in date from 1940-98.
  - Clearing Trail In Wartime (The PATC In World War Two), undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - One Man's Ancestors In The Civil War, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Setting The Stage- The 1940s, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A Changing Time And Place (An Arlington Native Recalls World War II and the Changes It Brought), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A Distant Time And Place (Growing Up In Arlington, Virginia Before World War II), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A Backward Look (Memories of The George Washington University of Fifty Years Ago, With Comments), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    General note
    2 copies
  - Breaking Trail In The Central Appalachians - A Narrative, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Photographs, 1998; MS0218 Series 2; 1 Linear foot
  This series consists of choral reunion photos taken in April 1998.
  - 1998 Choral reunion images, photographs and negatives, 04/1998 (Box SHARED Box 20, Box 2, Folder 1)
    25 photographs, 2 sheets of negatives, and letter from David Bates.